japan-rail-pass.com 2019-02-24

# Privacy Policy

1\. Who is responsible for processing my personal data?  
2\. What personal data is processed by Japan Experience and when is it collected?  
3\. Why does Japan Experience process my personal data?   
4\. What is the legal basis for processing my personal data?  
5\. Do I have to provide my personal data? 6. How can I manage my preferences for cookies?  
7\. How long is my personal data kept for?   
8\. Is my personal data safe?  
9\. Where is my personal data stored?  
10\. Who does Japan Experience share my personal data with?   
11\. What are my rights regarding my personal data?   
12\. Alterations to this Confidentiality Policy

 _ **1\. Who is responsible for processing my personal data?**_

The company Japan Experience, whose headquarters are located at 30 rue Saint-Anne in Paris, France (75001), is responsible for processing your personal data.

You can contact Japan Experience:

  * By mail at the above address;
  * By e-mail to the following address: data@vivreleJapan.com
  * By telephone on + 33 (0) 1 42 61 60 83.

 _ **2\. What personal data is processed by Japan Experience and when is it collected?**_

As part of its activity, Japan Experience is apt to collect the following personal data:

  * Surname, first name
  * E-mail address
  * Contact details 
  * Telephone number 
  * Bank details (card n°, expiry date, security code)

In addition, when you browse our site some data is automatically collected from your internet browser or terminal. For further information on these practices and to manage your preferences regarding this, please consult our page about Cookies. 

This data includes: statistical and session data, data concerning currency used.

The nature of the personal data processed by Japan Experience varies according to the situation which led to it being collected.

Thus, as an example, we only collect your banking data if you make an online payment using a bank card or our secure payment platform. In no case do we collect such data if it is not necessary for us to supply the requested service. 

We collect this data when you supply it or while you are browsing our site. This is notably the case when you provide information about yourself while making an order or when you are filling in the contact form for our site. 

_**3\. Why does Japan Experience process my personal data?**_

We process your personal data solely for the purposes of:

  * Dealing with an order you have made;
  * Monitoring an order you have made;
  * Contacting you with regard to an order you have made;
  * Answering a question you have asked us;
  * Sending you, having first obtained your express consent, newsletters and/or personalized commercial and advertising information.

We will never process your personal data for any purposes other than these without informing you beforehand. 

_**4\. What is the legal basis for processing my personal data?**_

The regulations demand that all processing of your personal data be backed by a legal basis.With Japan Experience, the processing of your personal data is founded upon the following bases:

  * The necessity of processing in order to fulfil a contract agreed between the customer and Japan Experience (processing/order monitoring and contact);
  * Japan Experience’s legitimate interests (reply to a question which has been asked);Your express consent (sending commercial and advertising information).

 _ **5\. Do I have to provide my personal data?**_

We require most of the personal data we request so that we can deal with your order. This required data is marked with an asterisk (*).

Communication of this data is obligatory in order to conclude an order with Japan Experience. 

If you refuse to provide Japan Experience with this personal data, Japan Experience will be unable to pursue your request for our service.

 _ **6\. How can I manage my preferences for cookies?**_

The issue of cookies is a specific one, so on our website we have created a page on which you can find information on this subject and manage your preference regarding cookies. 

If you wish to access this page, simply click on this link: XXX

 _ **7\. How long is my personal data kept for?**_

Japan Experience undertakes only to keep your personal data for as long as is necessary to deal with your order.

Certain legal provisions require us to keep your data for a minimum period of time.

Your personal data is kept by Japan Experience for the time periods set out below:

Customer contact details : 5 years  
Contact details in case of abandonment of order 15 days  
Banking data 4 months  
Cookies 13 months

Once these time periods have expired, we then delete your personal data or anonymize it. 

_**8\. Is my personal data safe?**_

Japan Experience, we take the safety of your personal data very seriously. This is why we have adopted internal measures which allow us to guarantee that your data is as secure as possible.

We have obtained XXX certification, confirming the quality of our computing system security policy.

If you wish to obtain further information about the security measures put in place by Japan Experience to protect your personal data, you can access the report regarding this certification by following this link: /privacy-policy  
+  
In order to confirm the quality of our security policy for your personal data, Japan Experience’s information system is currently undergoing a certification procedure which should soon be confirmed. Once this certification has been obtained, we will inform you by updating this Confidentiality Policy. 

_**9\. Where is my personal data stored?**_

Your personal data is mainly stored in databases located within the European Union.

Nevertheless, as part of the necessary communication of your personal data to our service providers ( _see 10 – Who does Japan Experience share my personal data with?_ ), this data can, in some cases, be transferred outside of the European Union. 

In this case, we provide you with a guarantee that such transfers are only carried out to countries which provide a level of protection which is equivalent to the one provided within the European Union or which have a framework of binding measures which meet the requirements of the applicable regulations. 

In addition, as we specify below, we provide a very strict framework regarding communication of your personal data to our service providers so as to guarantee maximum security. 

_**10\. Who does Japan Experience share my personal data with?**_

 **      10.1. Sharing your personal data with third parties**

The personal data collected by Japan Experience may be shared with third parties in the following cases:

• When Japan Experience uses service providers to host its databases. 

In this case, the Japan Experience website is hosted by GOOGLE CLOUD PLATFORM and its databases are hosted by Google Cloud Platform / Google Ireland Limited. Gordon House, Barrow Street, Dublin 4, Ireland in Belgium.

• When Japan Experience uses the services of a service provider as part of an order and according to the wishes expressed by the customer 

In order to supply the service requested by the customer and to meet all of their needs, Japan Experience communicates some personal data to its different service providers.

Thus, for example, when you wish to book a ticket to Japan, provision of this service requires communication of your identity information to the relevant airline. 

Similarly, when you pay for an order using a bank card, your banking data is communicated to our service provider, INGENICO EPAYMENTS, in order to benefit from a secure online payment platform.

The same applies every time that the execution of your order requires the intervention of a third-party service provider. 

• If the law requires it, Japan Experience can carry out communication of data in order to follow up claims made against Japan Experience and to comply with obligations arising from administrative and legal procedures;

• If Japan Experience is involved in a merger, takeover or asset transfer operation or insolvency procedure, it may transfer or share all or part of its assets, including personal data. In this case, you will be informed before your personal data is transferred to a third party.

In all cases, Japan Experience undertakes to:

\- Only communicate to its service providers the personal data of customers which is required for execution of the order.

\- Only communicate the personal data of customers to service providers who guarantee sufficient protection for personal data.

\- To provide a strict framework to the processing of its customers’ personal data carried out on its behalf by its service providers.

 **      10.2. Sharing your personal data within our group**

In addition, given that Japan Experience is part of a group of several companies, the other companies in the group are also apt to access your personal data if such processing is justified by the execution of the contract between you and Japan Experience. 

Thus, our counsellors, in our subsidiaries abroad, are available across a number of countries in order to answer customers’ questions during their trip to Japan 7 days a week. Their missions by definition involve accessing customers’ personal data in order to rapidly provide them with answers which are appropriate for their specific situation. 

In regard of this point, we guarantee that all companies in the TOURINVEST group are subject to the same requirements in terms of personal data protection.

 _ **11\. What are my rights regarding my personal data?**_

As part of our activity, we process your personal data in different ways. However, you remain the sole person with authority over your data and the what it is used for.

This is why you have the following rights regarding your personal data:

• You can access all of your personal data which is processed by Japan Experience;  
• You can update your personal data or ask for it to be deleted;  
• You can oppose the processing of your personal data;  
• You can remove your consent when it has been given with regard to processing of your personal data;  
• You can request communication of all of your personal data processed by Japan Experience in order to exercise your right to portability.

If you wish to exercise your rights, please contact our team which is dedicated to the protection of personal data:

\- By e-mail to the following address: data@vivreleJapan.com  
\- By mail, at the following address: Japan Experience, 30 rue Sainte Anne, 75001 Paris.

As part of the process of dealing with this request, we are apt to ask for proof of your identity so as to verify it.

In all cases, we undertake to provide you with an answer within a timeframe of one month, with the possibility that this period may be extended by two months in case of complexity or a high number of requests. 

Finally, we would like to remind you that in case of any claim or complaint regarding your personal data, you may make a claim to the competent supervisory authority. In France, this authority is the Commission National Informatique et Libertés (CNIL), whose website address is: www.cnil.fr

 _ **12.Alterations in this Confidentiality Policy**_

Japan Experience reserves the right to make any alterations to this Confidentiality Policy at any time. If an alteration is made to this Confidentiality Policy, Japan Experience undertakes to publish the new version on its website. Japan Experience will inform you about the alteration via e-mail, as far as is possible, a minimum of 15 days before they come into effect. If you do not agree to the newly written terms, you may request deletion of your personal data.

 **DATE OF LAST UPDATE: 30 May 2018**
